<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Pascal Cotret @ ENSTA Bretagne</title>
        <link>https://pcotret.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Pascal Cotret @ ENSTA Bretagne</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pcotret.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Lockdown setup - Working an IPEVO document camera</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/document-camera/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/document-camera/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As most of us, we&rsquo;re working from home for some time. Here is a quick start guide for the IPEVO V4K document camera.
Installation Hardware The camera itself is a plug-and-play device: it&rsquo;s recognized as a camera. Two buttons on it to enable/disable the autofocus and adjust the exposure.
Software Go to https://www.ipevo.com/software/visualizer#download
As you can see, the IPEVO visualizer is supported by several platforms:
In the following parts, we&rsquo;ll try to work with the Linux binary and the Chrome plugin]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Cisco cheatsheet</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/cisco_cheatsheet/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/cisco_cheatsheet/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Basic Configuration Commands    Command Purpose     enable Logs you into enable mode, which is also known as user exec mode or privileged mode   configure terminal Logs you into configuration mode   interface fastethernet/number Enters interface configuration mode for the specified fast ethernet interface   reload An exec mode command that reboots a Cisco switch or router   hostname name Sets a host name to the current Cisco network device   copy from-location to-location An enable mode command that copies files from one file location to another   copy running-config startup-config An enable mode command that saves the active config, replacing the startup config when a Cisco network device initializes   copy startup-config running-config An enable mode command that merges the startup config with the currently active config in RAM   write erase****erase startup-config An enable mode command that deletes the startup config   ip address ip-address mask Assigns an IP address and a subnet mask   shutdown****no shutdown Used in interface configuration mode.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Building Wireshark from source</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/wireshark_build/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/wireshark_build/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Prerequisites for Ubuntu 20 1 2  sudo apt install libgcrypt20-dev libglib2.0-dev libc-ares-dev libssh-dev libpcap-dev \ libsystemd-dev qtbase5-dev qttools5-dev qtmultimedia5-dev   Download and build 1 2 3 4 5 6 7  git clone https://gitlab.com/wireshark/wireshark cd wireshark mkdir build cd build cmake .. make sudo make install   ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Activate Coresight components in a Yocto environment for the Zedboard</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/coresight-zedboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/coresight-zedboard/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Activate Coresight components - Software side - Method #1 Generate a core-image-minimal Just follow https://pcotret.github.io/yocto-zedboard-101/. When booting this image:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  Poky (Yocto Project Reference Distro) 3.0.3 zedboard-zynq7 /dev/ttyPS0 zedboard-zynq7 login: root root@zedboard-zynq7:~# ls /sys/bus/ amba container event_source i2c media nvmem scsi soc usb clockevents cpu gpio iio mmc pci sdio spi virtio clocksource edac hid mdio_bus mmc_rpmb platform serio ulpi workqueue   No Coresight components 😢 ​]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Arduino Due vs. embedded C - ARM reversing</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/arduino_due_reverse/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/arduino_due_reverse/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[arduino-cli: Command Line Interface for Arduino ARM cross compiler: sudo apt install gcc-arm-none-eabi  Sample program We want to create the most simple program which goal is to light on the built-in LED, located at port PB27 on the Arduino Due.
Arduino 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8  void setup() { pinMode(LED_BUILTIN, OUTPUT); } void loop() { digitalWrite(LED_BUILTIN, HIGH); }   Embedded C 1 2 3 4 5 6 7  int main() { PIOB-&gt;PIO_PER = 1&lt;&lt;27; /* Enable port PB27 */ PIOB-&gt;PIO_OER = 1&lt;&lt;27; /* Configure PB27 as output */ PIOB-&gt;PIO_ODSR = 0xFFFFFFFF; /* Write 1 in all PORTB ports */ return 0; }   Codes and compilation 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9  $ ls -lR .]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Arduino vs. embedded C - AVR reversing</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/arduino_reverse/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/arduino_reverse/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As I was teaching some embedded C basics, I was asked what are some benefits of embedded C over the classic Arduino language for an Arduino-based board. This article tries to see what we can do by reversing a really simple program compiled with both methods for the Arduino Uno.
 Prerequisites  arduino-cli: Command Line Interface for Arduino AVR cross compiler: sudo apt install gcc-avr Optional: an Arduino simulator such as SimulIDE  Sample program We want to create the most simple program which goal is to light on the built-in LED, located at port 13 (or PORT PB5) on the Arduino Uno.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Quick start guide for SimulIDE as an Arduino simulator</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/simulide/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/simulide/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The idea behind this tutorial is to show how to install SimulIDE to run codes for an Arduino Uno board. Screenshots below were taken from a Windows machine. It will be the same thing for Unix-based systems (tested on Ubuntu). Some comments for the Mac port at the end (but it works!)
 Downloading tools  SimulIDE : v0.3.12-SR8 for the latest version. Download the Lin64.tar.gz or the Win32.zip archive depending of your operating system.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Aircrack 101 - How to get the password of a WEP/WPA2 session captured in Wireshark</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/aircrack-101/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/aircrack-101/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Prerequisites  sudo apt install aircrack-ng  Some wordlists/dictionaries. Kali Linux has already some of them.  WiFi handshakes 101 Introduction from @evilsocket&rsquo;s Pwnagotchi: https://pwnagotchi.ai/intro/#wifi-handshakes-101
Dictionary-based attack In order to test a PCAP with a given dictionary:
1  aircrack-ng -w &lt;wordlist&gt; &lt;wireshark_file&gt;   You have several dictionaries and sample PCAPs extracted from a Kali distro here: https://github.com/pcotret/aircrack-101-material
Wireshark captures https://wiki.wireshark.org/SampleCaptures One of them should work with a short dictionary.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Buffer overflow on ARM architecture</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/buffer-overflow-raspberrypi/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/buffer-overflow-raspberrypi/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Prerequisites  A RaspberryPi and a distro. For this tutorial, I had an up-to-date Raspbian Stretch Lite with LXDE. GCC and GDB.  ARM registers and stack TODO
An example of buffer overflow Initial state  We have a binary without its source code but compiled with debug information. We know how to use it: ./prog2 PASS where PASS is a 4-character string. We would like to know if there&rsquo;s interesting stuff or even dead code in it.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Comment faire des PCB avec des produits basiques</title>
    <link>https://pcotret.github.io/pcb-maison/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pcotret.github.io/pcb-maison/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Update 03/2018 : autre technique dans le labo d&rsquo;Heliox (propre aussi !) https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8joLK039fjk
De bas en haut :
 méthode de l&rsquo;imprimante laser mais trop chauffé méthode de l&rsquo;imprimante laser mais mal décollé méthode de l&rsquo;imprimante laser repassé au marqueur indélébile (meilleur résultat pour application &ldquo;industrielle&rdquo;) masque réalisé au typex, pas terrible car le blanco se décolle pendant le bain d&rsquo;acide. Je testerai avec du verni à ongle pour voir&hellip; masque réalisé au marqueur indélébile  Méthode de l&rsquo;imprimante laser : on imprime sur du papier le typon qu&rsquo;on souhaite réaliser.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
